

## CONTACT

- +8801748298776 +8801620833383
- asifimtiyajchowdhury@gmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/md-asifimtiyaj-chowdhury-7945a11b3/
- f facebook.com/asif.niloy.714/
- https://github.com/asifichy
- ) https://twitter.com/HelloChowdhury
- (h) https://www.hackerrank.com/asifimtiyaj
- Subject to blogger.com/u/2/blog/posts/7393187492704 601641?pli=1
- https://asifimtiyajchowdhuryportfolio.netlify.app/
- House-41, Block-E, Road-01, Bonosree, Rampura, Dhaka-1219

## **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor in Computer Science** and Engineering

**East West University** 

CGPA: 3.08 out of 4.00 2019-2023

### **Higher Secondary Certificate** (Major: Science)

**Birshrestho Munshi Abdur Rouf** 

**Public College** 

GPA: 4.08 out of 5.00

2019

## **Secondary School Certificate**

(Major: Science)

**Ideal School and College** 

GPA: 5.00 out of 5.00

2017

## **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Date of Birth: July 28, 2001 Marital Status: Married Nationality: Bangladeshi National ID No: 7365060438 Passport ID No: A02213237

## LANGUAGE

Bengali English



# MD. ASIF IMTIYAJ CHOWDHURY

Software Engineer, Cloud Solution Architect

#### **PROFILE**

"To be a part of a dynamic, progressive organization that will provide me the opportunity to grow professionally while utilizing my skills and experience in the area to add value to the organization. Along with being a software engineer and working with all of my passion, my life's goal is to be a good person."

## **SKILLS**

#### **PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES**

C, C++, Java, Python, PHP, JavaScript

#### **DATABASE**

MySQL, SQLite, Oracle SQL, MongoDB

#### MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT

- Android
- Flutter

#### FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React JS, Next.JS, Tailwind CSS,

#### **SOFTWARE QUALITY TESTING**

Selenium (w/Python)

#### SYSTEM ADMINISTRATION

Linux

#### **CLOUD SERVICES AND**

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

- Huawei Cloud
- Amazon Web Services
- Linux
- Terraform
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- CI/CD Pipeline

#### SCIENTIFIC RESEARCH

- IoT Based semi-automated robot for cleaning lake
- E-waste management

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **CLOUD ENGINEER INTERN HUAWEI TECHNOLOGIES BANGLADESH**

April, 2024 -September, 2024

- Huawei Cloud
  - Robi Datathon 3.0 (worked as a solution architect)
  - Terraform with Huawei Cloud
  - Deployed websites on CCE with Docker
  - Multi-stage Docker image build
  - Kubernetes
  - Linux System Administration
  - CI/CD Pipeline with GitHub Actions and Jenkins
  - o Participated in Training program of Banglalink Employees
- Amazon Web Services

## **SOFTWARE ENGINEER (WEB) INTERN**

February, 2024-May, 2024

#### **HEXEN**

- Web Development
  - Front-end Development
    - HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, ReactJS, TailwindCSS
  - Backend Development
    - NodeJS, MongoDB, EspressJS

## **EXPERTISE**

- Strong Leadership
- Team Player
- Research Collaboraiton
- Problem solving attitude
- Seamless Communication
- Time Management

## **ADDITIONAL SKILLS**

- MS Word
- MS PowerPoint
- MS Excel
- Data Entry

## **REFERENCES**

#### Dr. Md. Hasanul Ferdaus

Assistant Professor
East West University
Department of Computer
Science & Engineering
Phone: +8801799-687213

Email: hasanul.ferdaus@ewubd.edu

#### Md. Minhaz Uddin

Cloud Solution Architect South-Asia Cloud Business, Huawei Bangladesh

**Phone:** +8801878124795

Email: md.minhaz.uddin1@huawei.com